# **Jackson Beytebiere**

Seattle, Washington 98112 | 206-780-5357 | jacksongrowson@gmail.com Github | Blog | Linkedin

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in React and Redux. Possess strong skills in team-building and project management that help tech companies write efficient and clean code.Communicative and analytical. Engages with the public and community.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript ES6, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, R, Matlab

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## People Pages - Frontend | Backend

Social media website similar to Facebook

- Designed modular front end and built reusable components with React and Javascript ES6
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Applied Redux to create a powerful website with efficient and clean code
- Used Firebase allowing users to upload image files

## StockApp - Frontend | Backend

Stock portfolio tracker

- Used React with React Router to develop an interactive UI
- Implemented React Router to build a single-page application with client-side routing
- Developed a RESTful API using Ruby on Rails

## DavisList - Github

Craigslist-inspired site for making posts in a certain area or category

- Used Ruby-on-Rails to create a full-stack website
- Took advantage of cookies to store user information
- Extensive custom CSS code resulting in an appealing website

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **San Carlos Restaurant**

Bainbridge Island, Washington

Line Cook

08/2017 - 08/2020

- Directed the kitchen team to create quality meals efficiently resulting in faster service
- Ensured ingredients were stocked and food prepared each day for expediency

## **Tri-beta Tutoring**

Seattle, Washington 09/2016 - 02/2019

Science Tutor

Explained scientific concepts in easy to understand language to college freshmen students

• Broke down complex problems to individual learning levels helping students pass final exams

## **EDUCATION**

## **Flatiron School**

Seattle, Washington

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

08/2020 - 12/2020

## **University of Washington**

Seattle, Washington

Bachelor of Science

08/2016 - 02/2019